<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An abatement of most of the motions &amp; orders in chancery and other chargeable courts and of the greatest part of the charges which may be in those hereafter, or motions and orders reduced from twenty to two, and most of those to the tenth part of the charge, as formerly hath been / written by W. Leach, for the same intent, and tendred to the consideration as his former are.</title>
            <author>Leach, William, 17th cent.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1652</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 27 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 6 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A49858</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing L770</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R41233</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">31354596</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 31354596</idno>
            <idno type="VID">110209</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A49858)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 110209)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1743:8)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An abatement of most of the motions &amp; orders in chancery and other chargeable courts and of the greatest part of the charges which may be in those hereafter, or motions and orders reduced from twenty to two, and most of those to the tenth part of the charge, as formerly hath been / written by W. Leach, for the same intent, and tendred to the consideration as his former are.</title>
                  <author>Leach, William, 17th cent.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>11 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by E. Cotes,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>in the Year 1652.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imperfect: stained and with print show-through.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Court of Chancery.</term>
               <term>Civil procedure --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Court congestion and delay --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-07</date>
            <label>Leah Yurasek</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-07</date>
            <label>Leah Yurasek</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:110209:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>AN ABATEMENT Of moſt of the Motions &amp; Orders IN CHANCERY And other chargeable Courts;</p>
            <p>AND OF The greateſt part of the Charges which may be in thoſe hereafter:</p>
            <p>OR, Motions and Orders reduced from twenty to two, and moſt of thoſe to the tenth part of the Charge, as formerly hath been.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Written by</hi> W. Leach, <hi>for the ſame intent, and tendred to the conſideration as his former are.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed by <hi>E. Cotes,</hi> in the Year 1652.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:110209:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:110209:2"/>
            <head>
               <hi>AN</hi> Abatement of moſt of the Motions and Orders in Chancery, &amp;c.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">F</seg>Oraſmuch as in Antient times when the maſter Clerks of the Chancery (being in thoſe Ages very lear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned in the Lawes of this Nation) did contrive all manner of ſpeciall Writs then called maſter Writs very pithily, and well, ſeldome committing any errour or miſtake in any of them. And where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>as alſo the antient Serjeants at the Law in ſuch times did contrive and draw all ſpeciall pleadings in like manner, and then were all ſuits ſpeedily, and with ſo little Charge or trouble ended, as the people of this Nation did finde and perceive that they had full ſpeedy, and equall Juſtice done unto them, and did ſit down in quiet without multiplying ſuit upon ſuit, and turmoile themſelves in trouble and diſcontent many years together, as hath been too often uſed by very many of late, ſince ſuch maſter Clerks and Serjeants have been imployed about other buſineſſes (that is to ſay) ſuch maſter Clerks about References, Reports and Accounts, bringing them in much greater benefit. And ſuch Serjeants altogether, or for the moſt part taken up in moving and arguing at the bars of ſeverall Courts, and pleading at tryalls at the Common Law, and hearing in the Chancery, whereby few or none can procure them to contrive any ſuch thing: And (as it is thought) few or none of ſuch maſter Clerks can tell how to contrive, or draw any thing which before by ſuch their predeceſſours were in thoſe ancient times uſually done; by occaſion whereof Suiters in theſe latter times have been conſtrained to goe to Clerks or Attornies to have ſuch things contrived or drawn, whereof ſome (who have ſet themſelves forth higheſt) have been very ignorant, which many Suiters being but of weak or mean judgements or capacities could not apprehend; whereby very many miſtakes and errours have been committed and omitted in ſuch things which have cauſed many
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:110209:3"/>Suits and Cauſes upon Writs and Bills at Trialls to be loſt, and no further proceedings thereupon to be, but the plaintiſs therein forced and compelled to pay coſts to the defendants in ſuch Suits, and divers Ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dicts to be quaſhed and overthrown upon matter moved or ſhewed in Arreſt of Judgement; and alſo ſundry Verdicts to be reverſed and an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nulled by Writs of Errour all three of them many times the one after another, after the ſuiters in ſuch actions and ſuits have been at very great charge, trouble and labour, and great loſſes in the hindrance of them in their Callings and Profeſſions, and thereby many have ſpent very much, ſome as much as the very demand in queſtion, before they have, or could obtain their juſt debts and demands; and others have been ſo impoveriſhed by the means aforeſaid, that they have not been of ability further to proſecure ſuch ſuits for their Rights, but have given over, and loſt the ſame, and many inconveniences and miſchiefs, and ſuch charge and trouble, and loſſe, have happened in overthrowing, quaſhing, and delaying of divers Decrees, Sentences, and Finall orders in many Courts.</p>
            <p>And whereas of late time, moſt perſons in poſſeſſion of Meſſuages, Lands and Tenements, and wrongfully holding out others, have had the ſame by leaſe, or ſo claimed, and ſome of them held over their terme in the ſame; and many of thoſe alſo (who have had the immedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ate right of poſſeſſion of ſuch Lands and Tenements) have had the right to the ſame by leaſes, whereby moſt Suits in ſuch caſe have been brought, by actions of Ejectments, framed upon Leaſes which could not be tryed by writs of Aſſize, which hath been the moſt ſpeedy remedy in this behalf, and Judgements given at the ſame Aſſizes, when and where the Verdicts have been found; and many times one of the parties to ſuch Actions of Ejectment have departed this life between the day of the Tryall, and the day in the Bench, then next following, whereby all the proceedings before mentioned have fell to the ground, and the par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, their Executors or Adminiſtrators to begin anew, and by the ſame occaſion, Writs of Aſſize be grown ſo obſolete, that few know how to proceed, as they ſhould do in the ſame, and thereby moſt cauſes (which might have been proſecuted by Writs of Aſſize) have been begun and ended upon, and by ſuch Actions of Ejectment which have occaſioned divers of ſuch inconveniencies and miſchiefs as before are expreſſed. And whereas alſo in theſe latter times more <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ight hath appeared in all manner of learning to the ſeverall ſons of the people of this Nation, then hath in antient times (ten being learned in theſe times to one in thoſe; moſt ordinary people then depending wholly upon the Prieſt in moſt ordinary matters) and it is hoped the people here, will more and more increaſe in learning and judgement. And therefore it is expected, and deſired by moſt, that all manner of proceedings in Law ſhould be amended, and not run into worſe and worſe order, as they have done of latter years.</p>
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:110209:3"/>
            <p>And foraſmuch as great, and moſt pitifull lamentations have been made to divers perſons, in many places by multitudes of people (who have been turmoiled in Suits in the Court of Chancery, and other Courts, that many of them have been, and uſually are put to divers unneceſſary and exceſſive charges, by Regiſters and Enterers, and writers of Orders, and rules their Deputies, Clerks and Agents in ſuch Courts; and that divers unneceſſary Orders have been made in ſuch Courts by ſuch Regiſters, and others with them before mentioned, and drawn out much longer then hath been, or is neceſſary, and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to the note, or notes by them taken upon hearing, and debating of the matter touching the ſame, for their own onely lucre, trouble<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſome and burthenſome to ſuch Courts and Councell there, and hurt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full to the parties in, and to ſuch Suits; and that there hath been ſuch multitudes of Orders in thoſe Suits, that very many (who have pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecuted and defended the ſame Suits) have given long, and much at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tendance, before they have procured, or could procure any Entries or Copies thereof to be made, by reaſon (as divers ſuch lamentations have been) of money or rewards given, or promiſed to ſuch Regiſters, Writers or Enterers, their Deputies, Clerks; Servants or Agents to draw up ſuch Orders, or rules ſtricter, or to ſome other ſenſe then ſuch Courts did truly direct and order; under colour whereof very many have complained that many honeſt and juſt Cauſes have miſcar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried, and that in the ſame much charge, perplexity, trouble, travell and vexation have been to reſort to the Counſell in ſuch Suites, and afterwards to repair unto, or attend with Counſell, the Chancellor, Judge or Judges (who made, or pronounced the ſame Rules or Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders) to have the ſame drawn and entred according to the true ſenſe thereof.</p>
            <p>And whereas it hath been much complained of, that many others (who have not undergone ſuch perplexity, trouble, toil, and vexation, before they have procured, or could procure ſuch Orders or Rules to be drawn up according to the true ſenſe of the Chancellour, Court, Judge or Judges, who made or pronounced the ſame) have been at great charges in giving large rewards to Regiſters and enterers of Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders and Rules, their Depuries or Clerks (who have agited therein:) And alſo whereas the like complaints and lamentations have been, that ſuch Courts have been ſo full of buſineſſe, that many Suiters could have no proceedings there without great trouble and charge; and that divers before they have had, or could have any end of their buſineſſe or ſuites there, have ſpent as much, or more then that which they have ſued for there, hath been in value; beſides, their trouble, per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plexity and vexation of minde for many years together; and di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers others by ſuch occaſions have been quite, and others almoſt di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtracted, amd many utterly undone; and that many others have given over, and left off good Cauſes for loſt, and proceeded no further in the ſame, by reaſon of the extream charge and trouble, which they
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:110209:4"/>have not been able to undergoe after they have been brought into, and intangled in ſuch Courts, ſome againſt their wills. And whereas a great part of thoſe troubles and charges have been occaſioned by reaſon of the keeping ſecret and hidden all preſidents in moſt Courts (unleſſe it be in the Courts formerly of the Kings Bench; and Common Pleas, and now of the Upper Bench, and Common Bench, and Publique Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chequer at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi>) in ſuch manner, that ſome Suiters upon urgent occaſions have often been conſtrained to give to Regiſters, their Clerks or Agents in the Court of Chancery, and ſuch like Courts ſometimes five pounds, other times ten pounds, and other great ſummes of Money for choiſe preſidents upon ſuch occaſions, or otherwiſe have been conſtrained to goe to, and retain moſt Counſell belonging to ſuch Courts, and give them extraordinary large Fees for the ſame pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe.</p>
            <p>It is propoſed to be deſired that it may</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Be Enacced,</hi> That no matter in arreſt or ſtay of any Judgment, Decree, Sentence, or Finall order ſhall be moved, inſiſted upon, or given in exception, or aſſigned for Error againſt, in, or concerning any Plaint, Bill, Declaration, Information, Libell or Complaint, Preſentment or Indictment, Plea, Allegation, Replication, Rejoynder, Surrejoinder, Rebutter or Surrebutter, unleſſe ſuch matter be, or ſhall be firſt ſhewed and delivered in wring to the party or parties, his, her, or their Attor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney in the Cauſe, wherein ſuch matter be, or ſhall be intended to be moved in arreſt or ſtay of Judgement, or any thing therewith before mentioned, or aſſigned for Errour, in which the matter of Errour, or miſtake is, or ſhall be, (that is to ſay) what may, or ſhould be added to, or detracted from, or ſupplyed by further inſtructions in any ſuch Bill, or other proceedings therewith before mentioned, or continu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance or return of Writs, or proceſſe thereof, or entering up of Judge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, or any other thing therewith before mentioned, thereupon as cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain as if the ſame matter or miſtake were, ſhall, or ſhould be amen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded, ſuch Bill, Plaint, Declaration or proceedings before mentioned were, or ſhall be good and ſufficient in the Law: So that a true Copy, or true Copies of every of the ſame writings wherein ſuch matter or miſtake is, or ſhall be delivered to, or left for ſuch party or parties, his, her, or their Attorney in ſuch Cauſe at his, her, or their dwelling houſe or houſes, or moſt uſuall place or places of abode by the ſpace of two dayes next after iſſue, or demurrer be, or ſhall be joyned, or judgement acknowledged, ſuffered or permitted, or within fix dayes next before ſuch Decree, Sentence, or Finall order be, or ſhall be given, or to be given, decreed, or ſentenced in, or concerning the ſame Cauſe, Action, or Suit, in which ſuch proceſſe or proceedings be, or ſhall be.</p>
            <p>And that within three dayes after the delivery of ſuch Copy or Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pies, the party or parties againſt whom ſuch matter be, or ſhall be in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended ſo to be moved or aſſigned for Errour (paying unto the other
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:110209:4"/>party, his, her, or their Councell, Clerk, or Attorney in the ſame Suit or Cauſe, who doe, or ſhall finde ſuch Errour or miſtake, and deliver ſuch Copy or Copies in writing of the ſame, three ſhillings for the firſt, and one ſhilling for every of the reſidue of thoſe Er<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rours or miſtakes, may amend the ſame: And that that party and parties by, or for whom ſuch Copy or Copies be, or ſhall be ſo delivered within four dayes next after he, ſhe, or they ſhall have notice of the amendment, according to ſuch writing or writings, which be, or ſhall be ſo delivered ſhall again Anſwer, Plead, Demur, put in Allegation, Reply, Rejoyn, Surrejoyn, Rebut, or Surrebut, as the Declaration, Bill, Plaint, or other things therewith before mentioned, doe or ſhall require, unleſſe ſuch new matter doe, or ſhall ariſe, and appear upon ſuch amendment, that the Attorney of ſuch party or parties neither can, nor according to the courſe of Law ought to Anſwer, Plead, or to doe any other thing as before therewith is mentioned without further inſtructions, and then within eight dayes onely for every forty miles diſtance of the habitation, or abode of the party or parties, ſo again to anſwer, (when he ſhall be firſt ſummoned, attached, arreſted, or war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned to appear, or anſwer, reply, or to doe any other thing before there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with mentioned, to any-Bill, Replication, or any other thing before therewith mentioned) from the place or Court where ſuch proſecution be, or ſhall be. And that every one making default in any of the premiſes ſhall, or may be taken, or proceeded againſt for ſaying no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing, as for not anſwering, pleading, replying, or not performing any other thing therewith before mentioned, as hath been uſed in other caſes wherein defaults have been ſuffered.</p>
            <p>And that any who doe, or ſhall finde ſuch errour or errours, mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtake or miſtakes, ſhall have ſuch money ſo to be paid, to and for his and their own benefit and advantage: And that he or they ſo commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting, omitting, or ſuffering the ſame, ſhall pay the ſame money ſo for amendment to be paid out of his, or their own moneys reſpectively, according to the number of errour or errours, miſtake or miſtakes, as each of them doe, or ſhall ſo omit, commit, or ſuffer.</p>
            <p>And that after a Verdict, or Non-ſuit in any Action, Cauſe, or Suit, wherein ſuch amendment be, or ſhall be, and Witneſſes Exa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mined, Recorded and Certified, according to the Propoſitions for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merly publiſhed in that behalf, Judgement may, and ſhall be given according to ſuch Verdict, or Non-ſuit the next day in banck after ſuch Verdict or Non-ſuit, as of the day of giving ſuch Verdict, or ſuffering ſuch Non-ſuite, notwithſtanding the intervening of the death of any of the parties in, or to ſuch Action, Cauſe, or Suit.</p>
            <p>And that no motion or petition ſhall be made, moved, or preſented in, or to any Chancellour, Court, Judge or Judges in, or concern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing any Suit, or Cauſe there depending, but that firſt the matter to
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:110209:5"/>be moved, or mentioned in ſuch Petition, ſhall be put into writing, and a copy or note thereof delivered to the party complainant, Plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiffe or Demandant, Defendant or Tenant, againſt, or concerning whom ſuch motion or Petition be, or ſhall be made, moved, preferred or delivered, or to his, or her Clerk, Attorney, or Solicitor is ſuch Cauſe or Suit, or left at his, her, or their, or one of their dwelling houſe or houſes, or place or places of abode under the hand of a Councell lear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned in the Law.</p>
            <p>And alſo that within two dayes, or ſome other conv<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ient time, next after the delivery of ſuch note or writing as aforeſaid, for a Party, Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaint, Plaintiff or Demandant, Defendant, Defendants, or Tenant, his, or her Clerk, Attorny, or Solicitor in ſuch Action, Cauſe, or Suit (to whom ſuch note or writing be, or ſhall be ſo delivered) ſhall give, or deliver to, or leave as aforeſaid, for the other party Complaint, Plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiff or Demandant, or Defendant or Tenant (to whom, for whom, or on whoſe behalf ſuch note or writing be, or ſhall be ſo given, deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered or left) or to his, or her Clerk, Attorny, or Soliciter an anſwer in writing to ſuch firſt note or writing, or leave the ſame in writing at his, their, or one of their dwelling houſe or houſes, or uſually place or places of abode, and that each party may reply, and the other re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joyn, &amp;c. the one party of them after the other party of them, in, or by ſome ſhort convenient time in writing to be delivered, or left as aforeſaid till the doubt of the matter be, or ſhall be agreed upon, and put to the queſtion, or ſtated, as or in the nature of a caſe.</p>
            <p>And that if either ſuch party Complainant, Plaintiff or Deman<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dant, Defendant or Tenant, doe not conſent the one part of them to the demand or requeſt of the other of them, that then each party of them, who doth, or ſhall ſo petition, or have, (ſhewing or expreſſing to the other of them, ſome reaſon in ſuch writing, or note reſpectively; for what cauſe, or reaſon by, or according to the former preſidents or orders it hath been, and was requiſite and neceſſary that ſuch the requeſt of him, or her, who doe, or ſhall ſo petition, or move, ought, or ſhould be granted) that then, and not before, either of ſuch parties may petition to ſuch Chancellour, Judge or Judges; or to, or in ſuch Court for his, or her demand, in ſuch his, or her writing or note to be granted, and ſhew forth ſuch notes or writings on either ſide to be read, veiwed, and conſidered in ſuch Courts.</p>
            <p>And further, that if the demand or requeſt of ſuch motion or peti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, ſhall be granted or ordered againſt ſuch party Complainant, Plaintiff or Demandant, or Defendant or Tenant, againſt whom ſuch petition, motion, or demand is, or ſhall be made, (notwithſtanding any thing to the contrary thereof to be alledged, or expreſſed in his, or her writing ſo to be delivered, or left) that then he or ſhe for not conſenting to ſuch petition, motion, or demand, or for putting into ſuch note or writing, any vain or frivolous matter not materiall againſt
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:110209:5"/>ſuch requeſt or demand ſhall be compelled to pay to the other of them the ordinary Coſts, Charges, and expences of the other of the ſaid parties which he or ſhe, or they ſhall lay out, or expend, and ſhall make Affidavit before ſome Judge of the Court, where the ſame Action, Cauſe or Suit be, or ſhall be depending, if ſuch motion or petition be not, nor ſhall be granted upon ſome matter, for which there neither was, nor ſhall be any former Order, or leading Preſident in ſuch caſe.</p>
            <p>And that ſuch party (againſt whom ſuch Petition or Demand be, or ſhall be granted, or ordered as aforeſaid, or ſhall conſent to the demand of ſuch petition or motion of either of ſuch parties Complainant, Plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiff or Demandant, or Defendant or Tenant) be compelled to perform the ſame Petition, Order, Demand or Requeſt which ſhall be ſo gran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, ordered, or conſented unto without further charge or trouble, under pain and penalty, that for not performing the ſame, be, ſhe, or they refuſing, or failing in performance of the ſame ſhall forfeit, loſe, and pay to every perſon to be grieved or damnified thereby four times the value of ſuch value to be recovered, as is mentioned in other Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſalls<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
            </p>
            <p>And further to prevent exceſſive charges and troubles occaſioned by Regiſters and Drawers, Enterers, and Writers of Orders and Rules, and their Clerks, Deputies and Agents, that ſuch Regiſters, Drawers, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>terers, Clerks, Deputies and Agents ſhall, in, and to ſuch note or wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting, write what ſuch Chancellour, Court, Judge or Judges doe or ſhall order, or adjudge of, and concerning the ſame, and no more without re<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ar<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ing, or reciting any of the matters or contents of any ſuch notes or writings, and after that any of ſuch parties, or any, or either of them (within convenient time) ſhall ſet, or cauſe to be ſet down in writing, under his, or her Counſells hand, and deliver to ſuch Regiſter, or any of the parties before with him mentioned reſpectively, excepti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons againſt any part of the writing down of ſuch Order, and not otherwiſe ſuch Regiſter, or ſuch with him before mentioned ſhall at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend ſuch Chancellour, Court, Judge or Judges who ſhall make ſuch Order or Orders, and to alter or amend the ſame, according as ſuch Chancellour, Court, Judge or Judges doe, or ſhall ſigne, or write to the ſame, and after to enter ſo much onely in a book as ſuch Regiſter or Regiſters, Enterer or Enterers of Orders, his, or their Deputy, Clerk or Agent ſhall write, and ſuch Chancellour, Court, Judge or Judges ſo ſigne (if any need of ſuch ſigning be) in, or to ſuch writing or writings, with the parties names, and the day when ſuch Motion or Petition was granted, and to keep ſafe in an alphabeticall manner, ſuch notes or writings, together with the ſubſcription or writing one ſuch note or writing of ſuch Regiſter, or any of ſuch perſons before with him mentioned, ſigned by ſuch Chancellour, Judge or Judges, for fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther ſatisfaction of ſuch Court, or either, or any the parties, Suiters there, and concerned therein, if need ſhould require: and that Regi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters,
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:110209:6"/>and ſuch others before with them mentioned, may onely, take a competent gain for drawing, and copying of Orders and Rules (ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to rates uſually taken by Clerks for drawing, entering, and copying, wherein they have taken as much, or more pains then they in drawing, entering, or copying of ſuch Orders or Rules) upon, and under pain and penalty that every ſuch Regiſter, or other party before with him mentioned, tranſgreſſing in the premiſes, or taking more then before mentioned, ſhall forfeit, loſe, and pay to every party grieved or damnified, or to be grieved or damnified in the premiſes for every offence and default concerning the premiſes, forty pounds of lawfull Engliſh money to be recovered, as before is mentioned.</p>
            <p>And that for the eaſe and quiet of all Courts and people that all Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſters, and ſuch other perſons before with them mentioned (who have, or can come by any choice Preſidents or Orders of divers natures made in ſeveral Cauſes of ſundry natures upon ſolid, and mature deliberation) be deſired, or required that every one of them may, and will produce, and bring in as many of them in particular, as he in particular doe, or ſhall know where to find, or come by to be entered together, and that a method may be kept for the ready, and eaſie finding of the ſame to be viewed by any: or that the ſame may be collected together, and pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſhed in ſuch a method in print, for the purpoſe aforeſaid, that peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple may not remain hood-wincked and blinded of the proceedings and Cauſes of making Decrees and Orders in the Courts of Chancery, and ſuch like Courts as they have been, but that they may be informed and adviſed in, and of the ſame, as well as they have been in other Courts: And that ſuch Orders or Rules (as hereafter ſhall be made upon ſolid, and mature deliberation as aforeſaid) may be brought into ſuch Courts, and ſo entered, or publiſhed as aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>And that if any of ſuch Regiſters, or any other before with them men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned, doe, or ſhall draw up any Order or Rule contrary to the notes taken by any of them in any Court upon the matter moved, or argued, or to be moved or argued, whereupon ſuch Order or Rule ſhall be made, and the ſame be alſo contrary to that which ſhall be pronounced in ſuch Court, and ſuch Chancellor, Judge and Judges (who pronounced the ſame) or the major part of them neither do, nor ſhall juſtifie and main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain that which ſuch Regiſter or other party before with him mentioned ſhall ſo draw (though it be contrary to ſuch note or notes, taken, or to be taken) that then every ſuch Regiſter and party before with him men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned, ſhall for every time he doe, or ſhall ſo draw, contrary to ſuch note or notes, forfeit, and loſe, and pay to every party to be grieved or damnified thereby a 100 marks of lawfull Engliſh money to be reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered as aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>Whereas divers ſtubborn, perverſe, froward, and unconſcionable peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple, after they have been ſerved with Writs under pains, or Warrants to appear in the Chancery, and other Courts; and there to anſwer to Bils
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:110209:6"/>exhibited againſt them, have ſtood out Attachments, Proclamations, and Commiſſions of Rebellion, and proceſſes to Serjeants at Armes for many years, before they have appeared, or would appear; whereby ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny honeſt people of this Nation have been defrauded of vaſt ſummes of money by chargeable Motions and Orders, and otherwiſe.</p>
            <p>It is propoſed to be deſired, that for remedy thereof, it may</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Be Enacted,</hi> That if any perſon or perſons hereafter, being ſerved with a Writ or Warrant, commanding him or her to appear in any ſuch Court, and ſhall not appear, but ſtand out an Attachment, or other proceſſe, then when he or ſhe ſhall be Arreſted or Attached thereupon, he or ſhe ſhall be kept in priſon, or ſafe cuſtody, untill ſufficient Sureties be, or ſhall be put in, to and for the uſe of the Complainant in ſuch Suit, not onely for his or her appearance there, but that he or ſhe ſhall perform the Order of ſuch Court to be made upon the hearing of the Cauſe in ſuch Court.</p>
            <p>And that if ſuch perſon or perſons ſo ſerved, or warned to appear; and ſhall not appear within two months next after ſuch warning, or ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice; and the ſame be proved by the Oath or Affidavit of two honeſt Witneſſes, and of good ability in Eſtate, then may ſuch Court put the Complainant or Complainants in ſuch Suit to make proof of ſo much as he, ſhe, or they can, and after to proceed thereupon to hearing, as if ſuch defendant had confeſſed the reſidue thereof; and to pronounce a decre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tall Order, and award Execution thereupon: if the Complainant or Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plainants in ſuch Suit doe, and ſhall find, and put into ſuch Court, good, able, and ſufficient Sureties to make, reſtitution of that which ſuch De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant doe, or ſhall loſe, or have taken from him, or her, by vertue of ſuch Execution; if after his or her appearance, and anſwer ſufficient, and examination of Witneſſes in ſuch Court, it ſhall be there ſo conſide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red of, pronounced, or adjudged.</p>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
